export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The basic capability of a person is the ability to",
A: "create.",
B: "invent.",
C: "remember.",
D: "think.",
answer: "D. think",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. People who exhibit false identity do so in order to",
A: "achieve higher goals.",
B: "escape the realities of life.",
C: "obtain painful employment.",
D: "please their peei‘s.",
answer: "B. escape the realities of life",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Inappropriate behaviour of an individual is likely to result in",
A: "child labour.",
B: "inferiority complex.",
C: "justifiable actions.",
D: "strain family ties.",
answer: "D. strain family ties",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The knowledge of reproductive features of adolescents enables them to be aware of",
A: "their readiness for reproduction.",
B: "the needed care and hygiene of the body.",
C: "how to practise sex.",
D: "how to select the right partncr.",
answer: "B. the needed care and hygiene of the body",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. To promote national identity, it is iinportalit to",
A: "ensure high standard of living.",
B: "maintain a strong cultural hcritngc.",
C: "provide avenues for social mobility.",
D: "protect thc young generation.",
answer: "B. maintain a strong cultural heritage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. National symbols instil in the Glianaian a scnse of",
A: "ethnicity.",
B: "modesty.",
C: "patriotism.",
D: "royalty.",
answer: "C. patriotism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. Puberty rite should bc iiistituIioi›aIizcd in Ghana because it",
A: "acts as a check on pre-marital scx.",
B: "grants ruiduc £rccdom for scx.",
C: "enables pco;›lu to gct married.",
D: "promotes adoIcsccm fertility.",
answer: "A. acts as a check on pre-marital sex",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. One o‹itstanding socio-cultural practica in tine Glianaian society is",
A: "sensc of individtial values.",
B: "iiuclear family systems.",
C: "probleiTis solving skills.",
D: "cononunal living.",
answer: "D. communal living",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Marriage can be sustained by",
A: "fulfilment of the responsibility of the couple.",
B: "incoiiipatibility of the couple.",
C: "infatuation of ihe couple.",
D: "interference in the affairs of ilie coulpe.",
answer: "A. fulfilment of the responsibility of the people",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One ieason for whicli people contract inarriage is to",
A: "cscape from hard work.",
B: "bear and nurtiire children.",
C: "gain permanent eniployment.",
D: "securc traditional inl eritaiJce.",
answer: "B. bear and nurture children",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. A consequence of broken home is",
A: "child delinquency.",
B: "domestic violcnce.",
C: "incoiripatibility.",
D: "ilÆdGy",
answer: "A. child delinquency",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Provision of financial and physical needs of the family by the father helps to ensure",
A: "control over members.",
B: "effective use of leisure time by children.",
C: "equitable distribution of property.",
D: "liar iiioiiious living among members.",
answer: "D. harmonious living among members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. 1”hc fan›il¿’ «s nM inst it\iiion is impoitant because it",
A: "caters for both nttclcar and extended members.",
B: "gives financial support to members.",
C: "provides for children's education.",
D: "provides identité and sensc ofbelonging.",
answer: "D. provides identity and sense of belonging",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. .",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********.",
answer: "C. activity of bringing up a child",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. **********",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "B. family",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. **********",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "D. character formation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. **********",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "C. Tourism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. A Itlajor cnx'ii‘onmcMtal problem facing towns aud cities in Ghana in recent times is",
A: "land dcs'adation.",
B: "sound pollution.",
C: "»’aste disposal.",
D: "»’atci pollution.",
answer: "C. waste disposal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. \Y1iicli of flue following statements best descrlbes social change? The process of",
A: "altei in3 the behaviour of people iii society.",
B: "modify ing the political system of a society.",
C: "transforming society to meet new chalice es and aspirations.",
D: "traiisfoiaiiing the society through education and training.",
answer: "C. transforming society to meet new challenges and aspirations",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. One major iiiipact of fonilal education on national development is",
A: "cross-cultural understanding and national tin ity.",
B: "intellectual upbringing of the girl-child.",
C: "pi eservation of our cultural heritage.",
D: "respect for our traditional institutions.",
answer: "A. cross-cultural understanding and national unity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. One way of applyinp• independence and self-reliance to one's life is",
A: "insisting on doing things all by oneself.",
B: "leaving the care of parents early in life to fend for oneself.",
C: "having good education and professional skills to improve one's life.",
D: "soliciting votes from friends to become a leader.",
answer: "C. having good education and professional skills to improve one's life",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Political indepeitdeiice means gaining",
A: "freedom from one party rule.",
B: "freedom from autocratic leaders.",
C: "self-rule from colonial masters.",
D: "self-rule froln European traders.",
answer: "C. self-rule from colonial masters",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Declaration of state of emergency by governlneiits is a",
A: "lasting solution for resolving conflicts.",
B: "partisan way of ensuring peace.",
C: "short term solution to conflict.",
D: "way of testing the efficiency of the people.",
answer: "C. short term solution to conflict",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Peace building is effectivcly realiscd when flic Êc\i‹ling ›arlies arc",
A: "generous.",
B: "huinblc.",
C: "patriotic.",
D: "tolerant.",
answer: "D. tolerant",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. The t»ost disastrc is clTcct of clltnic conflicts in Ghana is",
A: "dcsti iictioM of yropcrly.",
B: "dis|›laccincilt o£pco|›Ic.",
C: "i»tci“ruption ofyrojccts.",
D: "loss of I tm an like.",
answer: "D. loss of human life",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. \VlJicli oftlic fnilo ving statcnzcnts he.st explains laissez-Zaire leadership? The leader",
A: "ircats follo vcrs like children who cotilrl least reason for themselves.",
B: "involves followers in dccisioiis aho it the affairs or‹Iie organization.",
C: "docs not iijtci ferc ii actiyitics, plans cuo dccisions of flollowcrs.",
D: "givcs orders without consulting hut expccts lzis or her orders to be obeyed.",
answer: "C. does not interfere in activities, plans and decisions of followers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. An autocratic leadership must be avoidcd in society bccause",
A: "foIIo›vers are gi'anted complète frccdoin.",
B: "ofits inability to liaiidlc emergency situations.",
C: "it identifies prohlen s for foIlo\vers.",
D: "it inakcs subörd(l1atcs fccl discontcnted.",
answer: "D. it makes subordinates feel discontented",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Unity and development are more sustainable in democracy because the people",
A: "are given the right to for in political parties.",
B: "are actively involved in decision-making.",
C: "elect their own local govei ninent officials.",
D: "enjoy high standard of living.",
answer: "A. Constitutional rule",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Which of the following options is a feature of democracy?",
A: "Constitutional rule",
B: "Controlled media",
C: "Primary socialization",
D: "Unitary party system",
answer: "A. Constitutional rule",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Regular payment of taxes niainly helps the govcivment to",
A: "pay internal rcvcnue workers.",
B: "pay treasury bills.",
C: "present internal borrowing.",
D: "provide social amenities.",
answer: "D. provide social amenities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Prohibition against the entry into military security zones curtails the individual's",
A: "freedom of expression.",
B: "frecdom of inovement.",
C: "right to privacy.",
D: "right to self-confidencc.",
answer: "B. freedom of movement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Sharing of ideas, cultures and iizcreascd interaction among peoplcs facilit‹itetJ fry technological skills rcFers to",
A: "co-operation.",
B: "globalization.",
C: "modcmization.",
D: "peace building.",
answer: "B. globalization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. The term iitIerit‹iIi‹JnuI cc›iiiiiiiiiiI)› rcfcrs In",
A: "all otlicr cotinlries aside Glian.i.",
B: "all countrics ouisid«A frica.",
C: "the industrialized cu‹mlrics.",
D: "the platforin of all iiiitioiis ariel tlicir pco|ilc.",
answer: "D. the platform of all nations and their people",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. folio\ving stalcinciJts is itnt nn objective of the New I'artnci ship for",
A: "Accelerating the empowerment of womcn in Africa",
B: "Eraclicating poverty in A ft'ican cotmti ies",
C: "Establishing ofsingle govcnHt cnt iit Africn",
D: "I lalting tile marginalization oFA frica in the global world",
answer: "C. Establishing of single government in Africa",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following options is a good avenue for saving in Ghana†",
A: "Colleagues at workplace",
B: "Credit Unions",
C: "Family members",
D: "Susu Collectors",
answer: "B. Credit Unions",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Which or the following options is not an avenue for youth training in Ghana?",
A: "Educational instifiitions",
B: "Political vigilante groups",
C: "Religious youth organizations",
D: "Youth wing of political ponies",
answer: "B. Political vigilante groups",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. One benefit of financial security to the individual is the ability to",
A: "grow money through lending to fi iends.",
B: "meet both unexpected and planned expenses.",
C: "borrow from other places to keep for the future.",
D: "regualate one's expenses without a budget.",
answer: "B. meet both unexpected and planned expenses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The body of knowledge acquired through systematic enquiry and considerable mental effori is tenned",
A: "research finding.",
B: "technical knowledge.",
C: "science.",
D: "technology.",
answer: "C. science",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. The promotion of science and technology education has reduced Ghana’s dependence on",
A: "Commonwealth scholarship awards.",
B: "expatriate skilled labour.",
C: "foreign consumer goods.",
D: "World Bank loans.",
answer: "C. foreign consumer goods",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. One factor that best explains insufficient exploitation and utilization of natural resources in Ghana is the lack of",
A: "capital to purchase equipment.",
B: "indigenous human resource at the rural areas.",
C: "industrial companies to employ more people.",
D: "training and retraining programmes for tllc poeple.",
answer: "D. training and retraining programmes for the people",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Which of the following measures is an appi'opriate way of prevenling the loss of quality human rcsource in G)zann?",
A: "Adopting road safety measures",
B: "Providing more recreational facilities",
C: "Improving quality food security",
D: "Encouraging in-service training for tvoikcrs",
answer: "D. Encouraging in-service training for workers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. A niajnr source of‹lcvclnyincnt problem in Ghnna is",
A: "rorcigncrs›voi‘king in hic country.",
B: "ina‹lcq\iatc inlcrljntional grants.",
C: "yoor j›riorilir1I ioi›.",
D: "World I3ank loaus.",
answer: "C. poor prioritization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The i test csscntial Facloi' needed in accomplishing cominui›ity computer laboratory project is",
A: "financial resouiccs.",
B: "indcntification oFtl1ojccl.",
C: "scnsitization of the pcople.",
D: "the support of the youth.",
answer: "A. financial resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. I» order to ovei'comc high cost of living in Ghana,",
A: "interest on hank loans must be maintained.",
B: "the rate o£inflatioi› must be allowed lo adjust itseJf.",
C: "the poyulatioi› growtl should remain at the present rate.",
D: "tlieie must he an increase in the production of goods and services.",
answer: "D. there must be an increase in the production of goods and services",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Ghana's economy is currently not buoyant because it is",
A: "heavily dependent on export of synthetic products.",
B: "heavily dependent on primary products.",
C: "highly industrialized.",
D: "highly politicized.",
answer: "B. heavily dependent on primary products",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. High level of education is cited as one of the causes of low population growth because",
A: "educated men are selective in their marriage partners.",
B: "highly educated women usually avoid marriage.",
C: "school years encourage young men to marry.",
D: "school years push child birth to later age.",
answer: "D. school years push child birth to later age",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The youthful nature of Ghana's population implies",
A: "adequate skilled human resource for exportation.",
B: "low dependency burden for the country.",
C: "potential manpower for industrial growth.",
D: "reduced unemployment in the country.",
answer: "C. potential manpower for industrial growth",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. People work mainly for",
A: "financial reward and donation to the needy.",
B: "financial reward and unplanned expenses.",
C: "money to promote national development.",
D: "money for personal use and charity.",
answer: "D. money for personal use and charity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. An entrepreneur can ensure sustainability of business through",
A: "dependence on bank loans.",
B: "maintenance of high quality products.",
C: "reliance on unskilled labour.",
D: "sales of shares to the public.",
answer: "B. maintenance of high quality products",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Ploughing profit back enables the cii1rcpi'enciii to",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "D. improve and expand business",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},



]